A Finding Aid to the Pietro Lazzari Papers, 1878-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lazzpiet
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1895-1998, undated; Series 2; (boxes 1-2; 1.7 linear feet)
  Morrison, Lillian: 1971 (1 letter)
  Mortot, Virgilio: undated and 1962-1964 (4 letters)
  Morvidi, Maria: 1918 (1 letter)
  Moskin, Ruth: undated (1 letter)
  Mullins, Mrs.: undated (1 letter)
  Museum of Fine Arts, Boston: undated and 1955 (2 letters)
  Museum of Fine Arts, Houston: 1964 (2 letters)
  Museum of Modern Art: 1949-1973 (3 letters); see Junior Council of the Museum of Modern Art
  Myers, Eugene Ekander: 1976 (1 letter)
  National Academy of Design: [1939] (1 letter)
  National Aeronautics and Space Administration: 1962-1973 (5 letters including 4 photographs of artwork and 23 photographs of astronauts Eugene A. Cernan, Ronald E. Evans, and Harrison H. Schmitt preparing for an Apollo 17 mission to the moon; an Apollo translunar/transearth trajectory plotting chart; an Apollo lunar orbit chart; and an Apollo earth orbit chart); see Cooke: Hereward Lester Cooke Foundation
  National Cyclopedia of American Biography: 1979 (1 letter)
  National Gallery of Art: undated and 1956-1974 (7 letters)
  National Housing Center: 1961 (2 letters)
  National Investigations Committee on Aerian Phenomena: 1957 (1 letter)
  National Society of Arts and Letters: 1952 (1 letter)
  National Society of Mural Painters: 1940-1963 (3 letters)
  National Student Art Tour: 1949 (1 letter)
  National Sugar Refining Company: 1938 (1 letter)
  Neale, Rosamund: 1961 (1 letter)
  Neilson, Robert Hude: 1928 (1 letter)
  Nelson, Helen Ewing: undated (1 letter)
  New American Library: 1953 (1 letter)
  Newlin, Ben: 1979 (1 letter)
  New Society for Art and Literature: 1947 (1 letter)
  Nichol, Jean: 1926 (2 letters)
  Nichol, Nella: 1929 (1 letter)
  Nilsen, Laila: 1946 (1 letter)
  Nobili, A.: undated letter written on reverse of photograph of Nobili painting
  Nuova Critica Europea: 1969 (1 letter)
  O'Connor, Don: 1960 (1 letter)
  O'Connor, FrancisV.: 1968 (1 letter)
  Oggi: 1967 (1 letter)
  Okamoto, Yoichi R.: undated (1 letter)
  Oklahoma Art Center: 1969 (1 letter)
  Oklahoma Museum of Art: 1988 (1 letter)
  Olson: Charles Olson Archives, University of Connecticut: 1975-1976 (3 letters)
  Oregon State Library: 1957 (1 letter)
  Orlando, Teresa: undated and 1949-1971 (3 letters)
  Ottiani, Giuseppe: 1909 (1 letter)
  Palmieri, Renato: 1928 (1 letter)
  Park, Marlene: 1979 (1 letter)
  Pavia, Dagoberto: 1959 (1 letter)
  Pavia, Goffredo: 1921-1924 (7 letters)
  Palmieri, Renato: 1957 (1 letter)
  Palombi, Angelo: 1921 (1 letter)
  Pan American Union: 1944-1945 (2 letters)
  Parsons, Betty (Betty Parsons Gallery): undated and 1949-1973 (9 letters)
  Passedoit Gallery: 1956 (1 letter)
  Pensione Boos, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Pensione Girardet, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Perentine, Giuseppe (Nino): 1927-1950 (3 letters)
  Peresson, I.: 1971 (1 letter)
  Peretti, Luigi: undated (1 letter)
  Perkins, Milo: 1944 (1 letter re: Ernesto Galarza)
  Perna, Giorgio: undated (1 letter)
  Peterson, Esther: 1978 (1 letter)
  Philadelphia Department of Public Property: 1960 (1 letter)
  Philadelphia Museum of Art: 1965-1966 (3 letters)
  Phillips, Duncan: 1954 (1 letter)
  Pirucchini, Maria: 1927 (1 letter)
  Pope Paul VI: mentioned in 7 letters dated 1966, including 2 photographs of Lazzari with bust of the Pope; see Fiore, Ilario; see Giovannetti, Alberto; see Institute for the Arts of the Archdiocese of Washington
  Preissler, Audrey: 1970 (1 letter)
  Print Collector's Quarterly: 1949 (1 letter)
  Print Council of America: 1963 (1 letter)
  Prospersin, Eugenio: 1941 (1 letter)
  Pyramid Club: 1956 (1 letter)
  Quick, Robert B.: 1972 (1 letter)
  Quinzi, Amerigo: 1920-1925 (2 letters)
  Rady, Cabell: 1958 (1 letter)
  Rahill, William Allen: 1954 (1 letter from Lazzari)
  Raker, J. M.: 1928 (1 letter)
  Ramakrishna-Vivekananda Center: undated (1 letter)
  Randall, Megan: 1975 (1 letter)
  Rassegna Nazionale di Arti Figurative: 1948 (1 letter)
  Rattu, Salvatore: undated and 1926-1966 (13 letters)
  Reeves, Rosser: 1947 (1 letter)
  The Reporter magazine: 1956 (1 letter)
  Reuther, Victor: see United Auto Workers
  Reynolds, D.: 1939 (1 letter from Lazzari)
  Rhine, J. B.: 1949 (1 letter)
  Ricca, Roberta: undated (1 letter)
  Rieder (?), Baronessa: 1934 (1 letter)
  Rioffo, Angela: 1959-1962 (2 letters including 2 photographs of friends)
  River Road Gallery, Louisville, Ky.: 1941-1943 (4 letters)
  Rivoi, Swami: undated (1 letter)
  Robson, John: 1958 (1 letter)
  Rocca Sinibalda: 1920 (1 letter)
  Rockefeller, Nelson A.: 1946 (1 letter)
  Rodman, Selden: undated (1 letter)
  Rollins College: 1933-1942 (4 letters)
  Roosevelt, Eleanor: Nov 09, 1945 and a letter dated 1964 concerns a viewing of the Roosevelt portrait bust); see White House; see Roosevelt Library
  Roosevelt: Franklin D. Roosevelt Library at Hyde Park: 1963-1965 (8 letters, including typescripts of speeches); see United Auto Workers
  Ross, Fred: 1949 (1 letter)
  Rosso, Giulio: undated letter of recommendation by Lazzari
  Roth, Maurice: 1993 (1 letter including 2 photographs of Lazzari's work)
  Rothschild, Anselm A.: undated (1 letter)
  Rowan, Edward: see Federal Works Agency
  Rowan, Leata: undated (1 letter)
  Rowantrees Pavilion: see Thompson, Lin
  Rowin, Fran: 1976 (2 letters)
  Rowland, Creelman: undated (1 letter)
  Ruffner, Willis E. (lawyer for Fanita Lanier): 1944 (1 letter)
  Russell, N. F. S.: 1932 (1 letter)
  Rust, John and Thelma: 1952-1954 (38 letters, including an application from Lazzari for a grant from the John Rust Foundation, including a clipping about Rust and 3 photographs of cotton pickers); see West Tennessee Historical Society
  St. Louis, Bertha: undated (1 letter)
  Sanderson, W. A. (Calouste Gulbenkian Foundation): 1958 (1 letter)
  San Francisco Museum of Art: 1967 (1 letter)
  Sartori, Guiolitta: undated letter from A. Guarino
  Satterlee & Smith, Architects: 1962 (1 letter)
  Savini, Renata: 1965-1967 (3 letters)
  Scheetz, June Rice: undated (1 letter)
  Schoenberg, Rose: 1967 (1 letter)
  Schurmer, Zaira E.: 1947 (2 letters)
  Schwarz magazine: 1957 (1 letter)
  Scigliano, Peppino Cosenza: 1910 (2 letters)
  Sebastiani, G.: undated (1 letter)
  Selmi, Gabriella: undated (1 letter)
  Sevareid, Eric: 1956 (1 letter)
  Sheen, Rev. Fulton J.: 1970 (1 letter)
  Simotti, Aristide (friend who was prisoner of war): 1911-1925 (62 letters)
  Sinisca: undated (1 letter)
  Sirony, Simone: 1955-1964 (8 letters)
  Smart: David and Alfred Smart Museum of Art: 1991-1996 (4 letters)
  Smith, George: 1926-1927 (2 letters)
  Smithsonian Institution: undated and 1947-1976 (8 letters)
  Snyder, Nell H.: 1969 (1 letter)
  Society of American Etchers: 1944 (1 letter)
  Society of American Graphic Artists: 1956 (2 letters)
  Society of Washington Artists: 1960-1961 (2letters)
  Society of Washington Printmakers: 1976 (2 letters)
  Sound View Press: 1991 (1 letter)
  Spiral Group: see Strantin, Wally
  Stevenson, Adlai: see White House
  Stewart, George: 1932 (1 letter)
  Strantin, Wally and Edward: 1950-1951 (2 letters)
  Stroppoghetti, Arturo: 1923 (1 letter)
  Stubbs, Kenneth: [1948] (1 letter)
  Studer, Alfredo and Clara: 1947-1976 (15 letters)
  Sweeney, James Johnson: 1949 (1 letter)
  Syracuse University: 1964 (1 letter)
  Taylor, Prentiss: 1972 (1 letter)
  Teller, Douglas H.: 1963 (1 letter)
  Terenz, Don Umberto: 1960 (1 letter)
  Thames and Hudson, Ltd.: 1974 (1 letter)
  Thomas, Norman: 1963-1965 (2 letters)
  Thomen, Luis Francisco (Ambassador from Dominican Republic): undated (1 letter)
  Thompson, Lin: 1950-1951 (3 letters)
  Thurston, Charles D.: 1927-1928 (4 letters)
  Tibet Society: 1975 (1 letter)
  Timpenado, Cesare: 1927 (1 letter)
  Tirrocelli (?), A.: 1917 (1 letter)
  Toledo Museum of Art: 1957 (1 letter)
  Toscanini, Arturo: mentioned in 2 letters dated 1928
  Tosello, Alfredo: 1947-1949 (2 letters)
  Tosi, Elisa: 1929 (1 letter)
  Treasury Department, Section of Painting and Sculpture: 1936-1939 (53 letters concerning the Arlington, N.J. post office, the Sanford, N.C. post office, and the New York World's Fair Sculpture Competition)
  Truman: Harry S Truman Library at Independence, Mo.: 1963 (1 letter)
  Turkish Embassy, Washington, D.C.: 1958-1959 (4 letters including a photograph of Lazzari)
  Tyler, Richard O.: 1958 (1 letter)
  Ugolini, Luigi: 1969 (1 letter)
  Ungar, Harold and Mildred: 1965 (1 letter)
  United Auto Workers (U.A.W.): 1963-1971 (9 letters); see Debs: Eugene V. Debs Foundation
  United Scenic Artists of America: [1939] (1 letter)
  United States Civil Service Commission: 1944 (2 letters)
  United States Department of Agriculture: 1945-1967 (10 letters)
  United States Department of Labor: undated (1 letter)
  United States Information Agency: 1959 (1 letter)
  United States Information Service: Jul 09, 1964
  University Settlement: 1946 (2 letters)
  Upham, Elizabeth: 1948 (1 letter)
  Van De Bries, Enri: 1973 (1 letter)
  Vangell?, Raphaele: undated (1 letter)
  Van Smith, Anne: 1949 (1 letter)
  Venice Biennale: 1948-1954 (3 letters)
  Vermont Marble Company: 1955 (1 letter)
  Veschi, Signora: undated (1 letter)
  Vickery, Ruth Bacon: 1929 (1 letter)
  Victoria Hotel, Rome: 1928 (2 letters)
  Virginia Museum of Fine Arts: 1956 (1 letter)
  Visher, John: 1956 (1 letter)
  Vosseller, Harold: 1948 (1 letter)
  Wagner, Edward A. (Dell Publishing Co.) and Julia: 1954-1976 (5 letters)
  Waldo, M. V.: 1945 (1 letter)
  Warren, Susan and Louise: undated (1 letter)
  Washington Gallery of Modern Art: undated (1 letter)
  Washington is Wonderful: see Jones, Dorothea and Stuart E.
  Washington-Lee High School: 1961 (1 letter)
  Washington, Walter E. (Mayor of Washington, D.C.): 1976 (1 letter); Oct 19, 1976 (1 letter from Franz Bader)
  Washington Water Color Association: undated and 1961 (3 letters)
  Watergate Construction Corp.: 1968-1969 (4 letters); see Don McAfee
  Watson, Ernest W. (editor, Art Instruction and American Artist): 1939-1949 (3 letters)
  Watson, Forbes: see Art in Federal Buildings, Inc.
  Weil, Frank L.: 1926-1936 (2 letters)
  Weinmann, Eric: 1980 (1 letter including a photograph of artwork)
  Wells, John K. (Equitable Life Assurance Society): undated (1 letter)
  West Tennessee Historical Society: 1952 (3 letters); see Rust, John
  Weyhe: E. Weyhe Gallery: 1949 (1 letter)
  White, Sarah: 1929 (1 letter)
  Whitney Museum of American Art: 1939-1980 (11 letters)
  Whyte Gallery: 1944-1950 (2 letters)
  Widdemer, Kenneth D.: 1928 (1 letter)
  White House: 1965-1968 (4 letters concerning the presentations of the busts of Eleanor Roosevelt and Adlai Stevenson)
  Whittemore, Manvel: 1936 (1 letter enclosing poems)
  Who's Who in America: 1979-1980 (2 letters)
  Works Progress Administration: 1937-1938 (4 letters)
  Workshop Center of the Arts: 1953 (1 letter); see Berkowitz, Ida and Leon
  WRC Radio: 1966 (1 letter including a photograph of Lazzari)
  WRC-TV: 1967 (1 letter)
  Young, June: undated (1 letter)
  Young, Louis Butler: 1971 (1 letter)
  Zerega, Andrea: 1972-1976 (4 letters, including a résumé)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, First Names Only, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Surnames Known A-Z, undated; (11 folders) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1895-1949, undated; (50 folders) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1998; (56 folders) (Box 2)
- Personal Business Records, 1925-1993, undated; Series 3; (box 2; 0.4 linear ft.)
  Personal business records include a lease, an appraisal report on artwork in Lazzari's estate, employment records, and financial records, which include a grant proposal, a price list, and receipts for the sale of artwork, purchase of art supplies and services, medical care, and travel.
  Employment records include salary records from the General Services Adminstration (1936-1939), American University (1946-1948), and the Corcoran Gallery of Art (1965), and employment forms from the Civil Service Commission (1944), the Department of Agriculture (1944), and the Washington Institute of Contemporary Arts (1950).
  - Legal documents, 1925, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Legal documents, appraisal report on artwork in Lazzari's estate, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Employment records, 1936-1950 (Box 2)
  - Financial records, bank statement, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Financial records, grant proposals, 1937-1966; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Financial records, price list, undated (Box 2)
  - Receipts, artwork by Lazzari, 1945-1976 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, purchase of artwork by others, 1954-1965 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, consignment receipts for works by Lazzari, 1944-1984 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, medical, 1975-1977, undated (Box 2)
  - Receipts, automobile (garage), 1938-1967 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, travel, lists of expenses for Italy tours, 1929-1962; (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Receipts, books, 1937-1961 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, art and hardware supplies, 1938-1981 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, bronze casting, 1958-1966 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, photographic services, 1941-1967 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, printing services, 1953-1966 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, shipping, 1938-1993 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, miscellaneous, 1937-1970 (Box 2)
- Notes, 1915-1979, undated; Series 4; (boxes 3, 13, OV 14; 1 linear ft.)
  Notes include two exhibition guest registers, address books, thirteen notebooks containing drawings and annotated diagrams, medical notes, astrological charts, notes on artwork and materials, and designs for inventions. A design for an exhibition announcement is decorated with an antique (18th century?) print of departing soldiers and ships, backed by a page of autographs, 1929-1931. Autographs include those of: Tracy Acosta, undated; Bobbe Arnst, 1931; Henry Mayo Bateman (cartoonist), undated; Hopkins, B. A., 1931; Laura D. Kuhn, 1931; Ernst Ludwig (?), 1929; Wilson G. Shugerman, undated; Maude D. Skinner, undated; and Johnny Weissmuller, 1931.
  - Guest register, unidentified art exhibition opening, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Name lists/addresses, address books, 1944-1946, 1964, 1966; (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Name lists/addresses, lists, 1945-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - Name lists/addresses, miscellaneous addresses, 1929-1974, undated; (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Notebooks, with architectural diagrams, musical annotations and drawings, undated (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with drawings, undated (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with drawings, 1917 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with diagrams, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with diagrams and drawings, 1948 and 1979 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with astrological charts, drawings, and diagrams from Prof. Rattu's casting class, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with astrological charts and drawings, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with diagrams and astrological charts, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with diagrams, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Notebook, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Notebooks, with diagrams and drawings, 1964-1972; (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Notebook, with diagrams, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Medical notes, undated (Box 3)
  - Astrological charts (see also sol 13), 1920-1978, undated; (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Exhibition labels, 1932-1955 (Box 3)
  - Notes on artwork and materials (see also sol 13), 1922-1977, undated; (11 folders) (Box 3)
  - Designs for announcements (see also sol 13, OV 14), 1955-1974, undated (Box 3)
  - Designs for inventions, 1915-1974, undated; (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Notes on maps and floorplans (see also sol 13), 1938-1968, undated (Box 3)
  - Page of autographs/design for exhibition announcement with an antique (18th century?) print of departing soldiers and ships, 1929-1933, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes (see also sol 13), 1923-1978, undated; (9 folders) (Box 3)
- Writings, 1910-1979, undated; Series 5; (boxes 4, 13; 0.4 linear ft.)
  Writings include autobiographical accounts and miscellaneous manuscripts, including "Giuseppe Stella" by Lazzari. There are also manuscripts about Lazzari, typescripts, and miscellaneous poems by other authors.
  This series is arranged as two subseries:
  5.1: Writings by Lazzari, 1992-1978, undated
  5.2: Writings by Others, 1910-1979, undated
  - Writings by Lazzari, 1922-1978, undated; 5.1
    - Autobiographical accounts, 1922-1977 (Box 4)
    - Poems (see also sol 13), 1935-1978, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous untitled manuscripts, 1922-1971, undated; (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts concerning artwork and materials, 1945-1977, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - "Why: A Book of Drawings About War,", undated (Box 4)
    - "Qualche Brano della Vera Divinia Commedia,", 1922 (Box 4)
    - "Atlantide" or "Cosmoplitana,", 1935 (Box 4)
    - "Giuseppe Stella,", 1964 (Box 4)
    - "I Carbonizzati,", 1967 (Box 4)
  - Writings by others, 1910-1979, undated; 5.2
    - Manuscripts about Lazzari, 1965-1979 (Box 4)
    - Poems, 1913-1965, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous untitled manuscripts by unidentified authors, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - "Morte di Proserpina" by unidentified author, undated (Box 4)
    - "Naughtolino the Wire Man" by unidentified author, undated (Box 4)
    - "La Bondine (The Swallow)" by Giulio Loccatelli, undated (Box 4)
    - Notebook of poems by Lazzari family members, 1910-1912 (Box 4)
    - "Problemes de L'Artiste Moderne" by unidentified author, 1948 (Box 4)
    - "Hydrogen Man" by M. J. Spivack, 1954 (Box 4)
    - 1"Milarepa, Tibet's Great Poet-Saint" by Dorothy Donath, [1963] (Box 4)
    - [Untitled typescript] by Mike Roma, 1963 (Box 4)
- Artwork, 1918-1979, undated; Series 6; (boxes 4-5, 13, OV 14; 0.9 linear ft.)
  Artwork consists of sketchbooks, prints, paintings on paper and an unstretched canvas by Lazzari. Loose sketches by Lazzari include 36 drawings of individuals at the Lindbergh kidnapping trial. There is also an antique (18th century?) print of soldiers capturing a prisoner by an unidentified artist.
  - Sketchbooks (see also sol 13), 1918-1960, undated; (22 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sketchbooks (see also sol 13), 1960-1979; (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Loose sketches (see also OV 14), 1913-1978, undated; (8 folders) (Box 5)
  - Sketches of individuals at the Lindbergh trial, 1935; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Prints and Paintings (see also sol 13, OV 14), undated (Box 5)
  - Prints, undated (Box 5)
  - Painting on unstretched canvas, 1972 (Box OV 14)
  - Artwork by others, antique (18th century?) print, undated (Box 13 (sol))
- Printed material, 1905-1994, undated; Series 7; (boxes 5-8, 13, OV 14; 3.8 linear ft.)
  Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Lazzari and others, press releases, programs, calendars of events, posters, miscellaneous brochures, books and booklets concerning art-related topics, miscellaneous publications illustrated by Lazzari, and reproductions of artwork.
  Books illustrated by Lazzari include the following: The Man and the Horse, undated; Nuclear Man, 1954; The Walking Cross, 1956; and Important Women of Washington, D.C.: 18 Drawings by Pietro Lazzari, 1961. Other books illustrated by Lazzari include: New World Writing, by the New American Library, 1953 (with an entry illustrated by Lazzari); Washington Is Wonderful, by Dorothea Jones, 1956; Merchants of Labor: The Mexican Bracero Story[autographed] by Ernesto Galarza, 1964.
  Miscellaneous printed material includes a map of military maneuvers in Northern Italy, 1909 and a blueprint for the layout of pylon and murals for UAW Regional Building, Grand Rapids Township, Michigan, 1967.
  - Clippings, 1905-1962, undated; (39 folders) (Box 5)
  - Clippings, 1963-1992; (9 folders) (Box 6)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for Lazzari (see also OV 14), 1924-1982, undated; (33 folders) (Box 6)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for Lazzari, 1982-1990; (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for others, 1938-1966 (Box 7)
  - Press releases, 1947-1981 (Box 7)
  - Programs, 1924-1994; (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Calendars of events, 1948-1951 (Box 7)
  - Brochures for schools and classes, 1942-1967; (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Brochures for artwork, 1937-1967, undated (Box 7)
  - Brochures for publications, 1948-1970, undated; (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Brochures about diabetes, 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous brochures, undated (Box 7)
  - Booklets, Artists of the Americas and Art in Latin America Today, undated (Box 7)
  - Booklet, La Divina Commedia: Inferno by Dante, 1927 (Box 7)
  - Booklet, Trois Sculpteurs Belges: Charles Leplae, Georges Grard, Pierre Caille, by Paul Fierens, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Booklet, De Como se Vive en Distintas Partes del Mundo, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Booklet, Lettera dal Mondo di La, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Booklet, El Nino y Su Mundo, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Booklet, Washington Water Color Association membership list, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Booklets, miscellaneous booklets concerning philosophy and religion, 1943-1956 (Box 7)
  - Book, Disegno e Colore Nelle Prose Carducciane, with essays by various authors (not Lazzari), undated (Box 7)
  - Book, My Personal Guide (astrology) by Ralph Creasy, undated (Box 7)
  - Book, La Danse de Civa (some pages missing), undated (Box 7)
  - Book, Anatomie fur Kunstler (textbook) by Carl Brunner, 1924 (Box 7)
  - Book, Mario Sironi by Giovanni Scheiwiller, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Book, The Poetical Journey in Old Japan - Basho translated by Yaichiro Isobe, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Book, The Mystery-Schools by Grace Frances Knoche, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Book, Egon Schiele by Gustav Kunstler, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Book, Despiau Vivant: L'Homme et L'Oeuvre by Waldemar George, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Avviamento alla Composizione (textbook), 1948 (Box 7)
  - Book, Pferde des Pheidias by Ernst Buschor, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Book, Tresors d'Art en France, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Book, Crin-Blanc: tire du film "Crin-Blanc" by Albert Lamorisse, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Book, A Dictionary of Abstract Painting by Michel Seuphor (with an entry for Lazzari), 1958 (Box 7)
  - Book, Stand Up, Friend, With Me: Poems by Edward Field, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Book, Norman Thomas: A Biography 9autographed) by Harry Fleischman, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Publications illustrated by Lazzari, brochures, 1942-1957 (Box 8)
  - Publications illustrated by Lazzari, engagement calendars, 1955, 1970; (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Publications illustrated by Lazzari, periodical, "No. 3 July 52 Poems,", 1952 (Box 8)
  - Publications illustrated by Lazzari, booklet, Hernan Cortes, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Publications illustrated by Lazzari, books, 1954-1964, undated; (7 folders) (Box 8)
  - Publications illustrated by Lazzari, miscellaneous, 1945-1962 (Box 8)
  - Reproductions of artwork by Lazzari (see also sol 13), undated; (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Reproductions of artwork by others (see also sol 13), undated (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (see ov 14 of 14), 1909, undated (Box 8)
- Photographs, 1878-1980, undated; Series 8; (boxes 8-12, 13, MGP 1, MGP 4; 3.8 linear ft.)
  Photographs (and 2 x 2 slide transparencies) are of Lazzari, his family, colleagues, his studio, models, art classes, artwork, gallery installations, art-related events, and travel locations in Italy, Kashmir, and the United States. There are photographs of notable individuals including Lyndon Johnson, Leslie Howard, and Johnny Weissmuller, as well as reference photographs of Edward Minor Gallaudet, Pope Paul VI, Eleanor Roosevelt, John Rust, Adlai Stevenson, Norman Thomas, and individuals at the Lindbergh kidnapping trial. Reference photographs also show miscellaneous industrial scenes, urban and rural locations, cattle, horses, and the circus.